Guide to the Russell Van Nest Black papers, 1919-1968.
Black, Russell Van Nest papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Russell Van Nest Black papers, 1919-1968.
3018
Black, Russell Van Nest,
47 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, printed materials, maps, publications. professional and organizational records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, notes, questionnaires, articles, maps, contracts, pamphlets, brochures, ordinances, and legal notices related to city and state planning, primarily in the mid-Atlantic states. In addition to his private practice, papers deal with Black's membership in the Commonwealth Club of San Francisco; participation in the initial activities of the Regional Plan Association of San Francisco Bay Counties.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Planner, landscape architect, civil engineer, author, teacher.
Russell Van Nest Black graduated from Cornell University in 1916, and later served as director of Bay Counties (San Francisco) Regional Plan, 1923; director of plans and surveys, Philadelphia Regional Plan, 1925-1929; vice president and president of the American Institute of Planners, 1933-1937; consultant to the New York, Pennsylvania and Virginia state planning boards; and consultant director to the New Jersey State Planning Board.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, notes, questionnaires, articles, maps, contracts, pamphlets, brochures, ordinances, and legal notices related to city and state planning, primarily in the mid-Atlantic states. In addition to his private practice, papers deal with Black's membership in the Commonwealth Club of San Francisco; participation in the initial activities of the Regional Plan Association of San Francisco Bay Counties; and various other state and federal planning efforts in the 1930's. Correspondents include Frederick J. Adams, Thomas Adams, Charles Stern Ascher, Tracy Baldwin Augur, Liberty Hyde Bailey, Harland Bartholomew, Edward Murray Bassett, Alfred Bettman, Frederick Bigger, Walter Harold Blucher, Harold Sinley Buttenheim, Gilmore David Clarke, Arthur Coleman Comey, Jacob Leslie Crane, Jr., Frederick Dohram, Earle Sumner Draper, R.F. Engle, Livingston Farrand, Carl Feiss, Benjamin Antrim Haldeman, Justin Richardson Hartzog, Henry V. Hubbard, Harlean James, Harold MacLean Lewis, Thomas William Mackesey, Albert Mayer, Eugene Davis Montillon, Lewis Mumford, John Nolen, Robert Randall, Irving Root, Ladislas Segoe, Flavel Shurtleff, Clarence S. Stein, Armand Tibbitts, L. Deming Tilton, Raymond Unwin, Lawrence Veiller, Warren Jay Vinton, Samuel Price Wetherill, Jr., Gordon Whitnall, Robert M. Whitten, and Henry C. Wright.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Black, Russell Van Nest, 1893-1969.; Adams, Frederick J., 1880-1945.; Adams, Thomas, 1871-1940.; Ascher, Charles S. (Charles Stern), 1899-1980.; Augur, Tracy Baldwin, 1896-1974.; Bailey, L. H. (Liberty Hyde), 1858-1954.; Bartholomew, Harland, 1889-; Bassett, Edward M. (Edward Murray), 1863-1948.; Bettman, Alfred, 1873-1945.; Bigger, Frederick Thomas, 1881-1963.; Blucher, Walter H. (Walter Harold), 1901-; Buttenheim, Harold Sinley, 1877-1961.; Clarke, Gilmore D., 1892-1982.; Comey, Arthur C. (Arthur Coleman), 1886-1954.; Crane, Jacob L. (Jacob Leslie), 1892-1988.; Dohram, Frederick.; Draper, E. S. (Earle Sumner), 1893-1994.; Engle, R. F. (Robert F.); Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939.; Feiss, Carl.; Haldeman, Benjamin Antrim, 1867-1955.; Hartzog, Justin R. (Justin Richardson), 1892-1963.; Hubbard, Henry Vincent, 1875-1947.; James, Harlean, 1877-; Lewis, Harold Mac Lean, 1889-; Mackesey, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1908-1976.; Mayer, Albert, 1897-; Montillon, Eugene Davis, 1883-1973.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Nolen, John, 1869-1937.; Randall, Robert, 1890-1966.; Root, Irving C.; Segoe, Ladislas.; Shurtleff, Flavel, 1879-1978.; Stein, Clarence S.; Tibbitts, Armand, 1891-1987.; Tilton, L. Deming, 1890-1949.; Unwin, Raymond, Sir, 1863-1940.; Veiller, Lawrence, 1872-1959.; Vinton, Warren Jay, 1889-1969.; Wetherill, Samuel Price, Jr., 1880-; Whitnall, Gordon, 1888-; Whitten, Robert M., 1873-1936.; Wright, Henry C., 1878-1936.; American Institute of Planners.; New Jersey. State Planning Bureau.; New York State Planning Board.; Pennsylvania State Planning Board.; Philadelphia Regional Plan.; Regional Plan Association of Bay Counties.; Virginia. State Planning Board.
Subjects:
City planning.; Regional planning.; City planners -- United States.; Landscape architects -- United States.; City planners; Landscape architects
Places:
United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Questionnaires.; Maps.; Contracts.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Client Files
Allentown, Pennsylvania
Clients B - D
Clients E - Mercer County
Clients M - R
Clients S - Z
Dead Job Files
Series III. Philadelphia Regional Plan
Series IV. Subject Files
A - H
Highway - Housing
Industry - Legislation
L - M
N-Parks, Parkways and Playgrounds
PL - PR
R - Transportation
U - Zoning Ordinances
Zoning: Trial Notices, Clippings
A - L
M-Z
Unsorted
Series V. Russell Black Consulting Reports
A-L
M-New Jersey
P-Z
Pennsylvania: Allentown - Lower Makefield
Pennsylvania: Lower Paxton - Z
Series VI. American Institute of Planners
Series VII. Manuscripts and Research
Manuscripts by Black
Building Line Research (1933)
Articles by Black and Others
Series VIII. Graphic Materials
Series IX. Plans and Maps by Russell Black
California, Florida, Idaho, and Texas
New Jersey and New York
Pennsylvania
Miscellaneous or Unknown Location
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  Arranged alphabetically within each date range.
  - 1919-1922
    - A - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      City Planning American Falls, Idaho; Zoning - Hightstown, New Jersey. American City Magazine
    - A - file, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Aurora, Illinois; American Falls, Idaho; Miniodoka, Idaho
    - A - file, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Aurora, Illinois; Ashtabule, Ohio; Appleton, Wisconsin. Highway Planning - Akron, Ohio
    - B - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Boise, Ohio; Stockton, California;Tacoma Park, Maryland; Hightstown, New Jersey
    - B - file, 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Boise, Idaho; American Falls, Idaho. American City Magazine
    - C - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Corning, New York; Columbus, Ohio; Hightstown, New Jersey. Waldo S. Coulter.
    - C - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      City Planning Profession - Cornell University
    - D - file, 1919-1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      City Planning Profession - Hightstown, New Jersey. Cornell University. Gordon Davis.
    - E - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      City Planning Profession - Elmira, New York; Evansville, Indiana; Elmira Chamber of Commerce
    - F - file, 1920, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Trenton, New Jersey; Freehold, New Jersey; Elmira, New York. Henry Ford; Mayor W. S. Holmes.
    - G - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Profession - Park System
    - H - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Hightstown, New Jersey; Trenton, New Jersey; Highland Parks, New Jersey.
    - I - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Ithaca, New York. American City Planning Institute
    - K; L - file, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - M - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - N - file, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Trenton, New Jersey; Akron, Ohio. John Nolen
    - N - file, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Akron, Ohio. John Nolen.
    - O; P; Q - file, 1920, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Town Planning - Hightstown, New Jersey
    - R - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Richmond, Virginia; Ridgewood, New Jersey
    - R - file, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Professional Practice. American Society of Landsacpe Architecture. Frederick L. Olmsted.
    - S - file, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Professional Practice. Flavel Shurtleff
    - T - file, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Trenton, New Jersey.
    - W; V; Y - file, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1921-1923
    - A - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - B - file, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Santa Barbara, California; Ventura, California; Hightstown, New Jersey. Harland Bartholomew; Morris Bien; Ekawrd M. Bassett.
    - C - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Ventura, California; San José, California
    - D - file, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Ithaca, New York. Gordon Davis; E.S. Draper.
    - E - file, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Eau Claire, Wisconsin; Berkeley, California.
    - F - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Fresno, California
    - G - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Ventura, California; Fresno, California. Edward Glass.
    - H - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Santa Barbara, California; Ventura, California; Ithaca New York; Evergreen Farm, New Jersey. Justin Hartzog.
    - I - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Ithaca, New York.
    - K - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - L - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Ventura, California; Lodi, California.
    - M - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Monrovia, California.
    - N - file, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Oakland, California; Los Angeles, California. John Nolen.
    - O - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Oakland, California; Ontario, California. Planning Commission, City of Oakland.
    - P - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - R - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Riverside, California; Redlands, California. Irving Root.
    - S - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      San Diego, California; Santa Paula, California; Stockton, California; Superior, Wisconsin. M. Vrmy Seares.
    - T - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Hightstown, New Jersey. Armand Tibbitts.
    - U-V - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Ventura, California; Vincennes, Indiana.
    - W - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Waukesha, Wisconsin; Wausau, Wisconsin. Gordon Whitehall
  - 1923-1924
    - A - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Anaheim, California; Ventura, California
    - B - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      San Francisco Bay, California; American Falls, Idahos; Baltimore, Maryland. Harland Bartholomew; Edward Bassett.
    - C - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      San Francisco Bay, California; Akron, Ohio. Commonwealth Club of California.
    - D - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Education. Cornell University. Gordon Davis
    - E - file, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      (Eureka, California)
    - F - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - G - file, 1921; 1923 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - H - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Hightstown, New Jersey; Long Beach, California. Antrim Haldeman; Justin Hartzog
    - I - file, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      Ithaca, New York. Liberty Hyde Bailey
    - K - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      Venice, California, Playa del Rey, California.
    - L - file, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      Long Beach, California.
    - M - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Marysville, California; Monterey, California.
    - Mc - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      Landscape Planning - Hightstown New Jersey
    - N - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      San Diego, California; San Francisco, California; Long Beach, California. John Nolen.
    - O - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      Oxnard, California
    - P - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      Park Planning - Palo Alto, California
    - R - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      Profession. Irving Root; Robert Randall
    - S - files, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 61-62)
      San Diego, California; San Francisco Bay, California; San José, California; Stockton, California; Salinas, California; Culver, California; Santa Barbara, California; Santa Monica, California. Flavel Shurtleff; Barbara Dacier.
    - T - file, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      Hightstown, New Jersey.
    - U-V - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      San Buenaventura, California; Ventura, California. Office of the City Attorney
    - W - file, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      Santa Barbara, California. Gordon Whitehall.
    - XYZ - file, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      Yuba City, California
  - 1925-1930
    - A - file, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      Harold Buttenheim
    - A - file, 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Applications for Position, 1925-1926, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Applications for Membership - Associations, Societies, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - American City Planning Institute, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 72)
      Flavel Shurtleff; Robert Witten; Harland Bartholomew
    - Auburn, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 73)
      City Planning -Correspondence
    - B General, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - B - file, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Bucks County Farm, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - C General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Charleston. Gilmore Clark
    - C - file, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - D General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Landscape Department - Cornell; Planning Foundation of America
    - D - file, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Hamden, Connecticut; Hightstown, New Jersey; San Francisco, California; Chimney Rock. Rotary mile. Frederick Dohrmann; E. S. Draper; Frederick Davis.
    - Department of Commerce Reports, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Division of Building and Housing Bureau of Standards
    - E - General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Park Plantings
    - E - file, 1925-1926, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Endicott, New York. American Society of Civil Engineers Meeting.
    - Engineers Club, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Pennsylvania
    - Engineers Club Committees, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - F - file, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Hightstown, New Jersey; Fulton, New York. American City Planning Institute; American Association of Nurserymen; American Society of Civil Engineers.
    - G General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Mercer County, New Jersey.
    - G - file, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Geneva, New York. Books. History
    - H General - file, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Mercer County, New Jersey; Kansas City, Kansas; Hamilton Township, New Jersey; Hartford Connecticut. "Theory - Planning the Region as Exemplified by the Philadelphia Tri-State Plan". Henry Hubbard; Justin Hartzog
    - H - file, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      School Planning - Peddie School; Hightstown, New Jersey; Ithaca, New York; Hornell, New York. Justin Hartzog
    - House: Mortgages and Insurance, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Ithaca, New York. Renwick Road House
    - I - file, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Miscellaneous
    - Ithaca, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Ithaca, New York. "Rotary Mile" Studies. Recreational Planning.
    - J General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - J - file, 1925, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Jamestown, New York
    - K General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Spokane, Washington.
    - K - file, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Keene, New Hampshire; Norfolk, Connecticut; Kent, Ohio.
    - L General, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Passaic County, New Jersey. New Jersey Planning Commissions.
    - L - file, 1925, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Lima, Ohio; Lorain, Ohio; Lyons, New York. Frederick Loeb
    - Lectures (Manuscripts), 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Talk at Yardley, Pennsylvania; Talk at Middleton, New Jersey; Lecture at RPPA Meeting - "Effective Planning and How it May be Accomplished"; "Zoning and Its Relation to Board Municipal Planning"; "Can Intelligent Zoning be Done Without a Comprehensive City Plan?"; "Theory of the Regional Plan"; "Theory of the Region as Exemplified by Philadelphia Tri-State Plan"
    - Lynchburg, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Lynchburg, Virginia. R. W. B. Hart, City Manager.
    - M - file, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Morris Plains, New Jersey; Montclair, New Jersey; Freehold, New Jersey; Morrisville, Pennsylvania. Cornell Planning Lectures.
    - M - file, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Princeton, New Jersey; Bridgeton, New Jersey
    - M - file, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Wife's Letters
    - Mailing List - file, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Model City, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Exhibit at 1933 Chicago World's Fair. Harland Bartholomew; Harold Buttenheim
    - N General, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Chester Pennsylvania Review: "County Parks"; Housing Development Philadelphia, Pennslyvania; Chicago Fair Exhibition; Housing Needs of the Modern Family". John Nolen; Wayne Heydecker.
    - N - file, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Landscape Design - Ithaca, New York; Norwich, New York; Norwalk Connecticut. Planning Foundation of America. John Nolen; Flavel Shurtleff.
    - Mr. Nolen, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; San Francisco, California
    - P General, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Pennsauken Township; New Jersey. "Aesthetics of Zoning"
    - P - file, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Peekskill, New York; Princeton, New Jersey. Peddie School.
    - Personal (Typed Reports), 1928 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Philadelphia Tri-State; Regional Government Administration.
  - 1923-1930
    - Personal Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Philadelphia Regional Plan, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Howard Strong. Philadelphia Regional Plan
    - Phinney, Sedley H., 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      New Jersey. Edward M. Bassett. New Jersey State League of Municipalities.
    - Planning Foundation of America, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Mercer County, New Jersey; Middlesex, New Jersey. L. Purdy; F. Shurtleff.
    - Planning Foundation of America, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      California. F. Fhurtleff; W. S. Olds.
    - R General, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Hartford, Connecticut; Reading Pennsylvania. Robert Randall; Frederick Willson; Irving Root.
    - R - file, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Irving Root; Robert Randall.
    - Regional Planning Federation - Philadelphia Tri-State, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Philadelphia Tri-State.
    - Requests for Pamphlets, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - S General, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - S - file, 1925-1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Seneca, New York; Palo Alto, California; Syracuse, New York. National Conference on City Planning. Flavel Shurtleff; Charles Sumner; Leopold Schepp.
    - San Francisco Regional Plan, 1923-1926 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Chicago, Illinois; Niagara. City Planning Societies. Frederick Dohrman; Flavel Shurtleff; John Nolen; Frederick Reed.
    - Santa Clara, California, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      George Sullivan
    - Lewis Lawrence Smith, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Lewis Lawrence Smith Property, Delaware County.
    - T General, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Cobleskill, New York. L.D. Tilton; Armand Tibbitts.
    - T - file, 1926-1929 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Norwalk, Connecticut; Hightstown, New Jersey
    - Armand Tibbitts, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Peekskill, New York; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Princeton, New Jersey.
    - U General, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Park Planning - Middlesex County, New Jersey.
    - U - file, 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Pennsylvania; Raymond Unwin.
    - V General, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Ventura, California. Review: John Nolen's "City Planning:. Lawrence Veiller. National Housing Association
    - V - file, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Zoning Bibliographical Suggestions. Lawrence Veiller. National Housing Association
    - W General, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      San Francisco, California; New Jersey; Williamsport, Pennsylvania. Regional Plan Competition - Madrid. Gordon Whitehall; Henry Wright.
    - W - file, 1925-1929 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Hightstown, New Jersey; Princeton, New Jersey; Wellsville, New York. Samuel P. Wetherill; Henry Wright
    - X-Y General, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Lectures - Cornell. College of Architecture. George Young, Jr.
    - XYZ - file, 1925-1957, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      George Young
    - Chamber of Commerce and roadside development, 1929-1930 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Copies, 1929-1930 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      Copies of correspondence between Black, John Nolan, and William Connell
  - 1931
    - A General - file, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Princeton, New Jersey; Mercer County, New Jersey. Chicago World's Fair. American City. Tracy Augur; Harold Buttenheim; Harlean James.
    - American City Planning Institution, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      New Jersey; Pennslyvania. ACPI Constitutional Changes. Flavel Shurtleff; Alfred Bettman
    - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - American Society of Landscape and Architecture, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Clarence Fowler
    - Applications, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - B General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Princeton, New Jersey. City Planning History.
    - B Prospects, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Beach Haven, New Jersey; Bergen New Jersey; Burlington, New Jersey. W. R. Conard; R. Engle.
    - Bound Brook, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      George La Monte; Major Fetterly.
    - C General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Brooklyn, New York. Park Planning Competition. Gilmore Clark; Jacob Crane
    - C Prospects, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Coatesville, Pennsylvania.
    - Cornell University, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Cornell Lecture Series. Gilmore Clark; Tracy Augur; Alfred Bettman; Clarence Stein; Eugene Montillon; Justin Hartzog; John Nolen; Flavel Shurleff; Jacob Crane.
    - D - file, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Mercer County Plan. F. Dohrmann.
    - E General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Monclair, New Jersey. Pollution; National State Parks. Bernard B. Eddy; Engineering Club
    - E Prospects, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Elmira, N; Englewood, New Jersey. Allan Hoffman; Alexander Livingston.
    - F General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - William Flemer, Jr, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Princeton Farms, Inc., New Jersey. W. Flemer, Jr; Princeton Nursery.
    - G General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      American Road Builders Association
    - H General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Pennsylvania. "Zoning Accomplishments and Administration". H. Hubbard
    - H Prospects, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Hamilton Township, New Jersey; Hamilton, New Jersey. Hamilton Township Committee.
    - I General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Ithaca, New York. George Tarbell
    - J Prospects, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Jamestown, New York. Ernest Lawcroft. City Planning Commission.
    - K General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Montclair, New Jersey. Kaveny
    - L General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - La Monte, George - Estate, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Lawrence Township, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Little Falls, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Mrs. S. J. Francisco
    - Lynchburg, Virginia, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - M General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Montclair, New Jersey.
    - M Prospects, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Mercer County, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Middlesex County, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Model City, World's Fair, 1933, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      Model City. Harold Buttenheim. American City.
    - Monroe County, New York, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Moorestown, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Highway Planning. Louis Klauder. Moorestown Improvement Association
    - Morris County, New Jersey, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      Highway Planning. George Farny. National Highway Association
    - N General, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 52)